SURAPOS APHARATVILAI

Bangkok, Thailand 🏦

+66899965999 \$

surapos999@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Deadline-Oriented developing professional with over 5 years of experience in IT industry. With my years of experience in international corporates and working closely with wide range of highly diversified and talented teams as well as senior stakeholders and business owners, and so developing into a professional leader myself is something I'm keen on in the near future. Having experience in both Waterfall and Agile software development methodology, I'm a skilled Business Analyst focusing on end-to-end process and operations improvement in IT industry. Currently holding an MBA degree from Coventry University and is a certified Professional Scrum Master.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

BUSINESS ANALYST / BRED IT (THAILAND) LTD.

Project Name: Triparty – End of Month Processing Web Application for Capital Market Responsibilities:

- Collaborate with developers to identify field-mapping and business rules from coding developed from another project
- Prepared a pivot table containing relevant data to be used to create a new Harmonized Data table; bringing together data from different agents of varying file formats, naming conventions, and columns, and transforming it into one harmonized data table
- Assist Product Owner in preparing Functional Specification Document
- Perform functional testing in UAT

Project Name: Mifid – Front-End Web Application Dashboard on Regulatory Reports for Capital Market Responsibilities:

- Analyze Functional Specification Document from Product Owner in France and break-down requirements into user stories
- Developed business document containing field mappings and business rules
- Developed and propose UI Dashboard screens and functionality to business stakeholders
- Developed User Manual and Guidelines
- Lead grooming session with developers and QA
- Perform functional testing in DEV environment and execute UAT
- Perform sprint review with Product Owner and business stakeholders
- Participate in Sprint Retrospective session

Project Name: Justification of Late Operations (JOT) – Risk and Compliance Web Application for Capital Market

Responsibilities:

- Analyze and create user stories to comply with Audit recommendations
- Managed backlog and sprint for development deliveries
- Collaborate with developer to look for potential enhancement for better user-experience
- Prepared test plan consisting of test-cases for each sprint
- Execute tests in DEV and UAT
- Developed User Manual and Guidelines
- Prepared documentation and checklist to on-board new users into the application

JULY 2019 – SEPTEMBER 2020

CONSULTANT / CAPCO CONSULTANCY THAILAND

Project Name: SCB – IMEX Trade Finance for Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam Responsibilities:

- Plan scope of work and activities for business requirement gathering phase
- Lead meeting with project stakeholders and SCB Vietnam oversea branch
- Lead and developed Gap Analysis document for SCB Vietnam branch
- Developed User Request document for internal resource reservation for project implementation
- Developed Functional Specification Document (FSD) for SCB Vietnam to sign-off
- Developed Vendor Enhancement Specification to sign-off on identified gaps
- Assisted Project Manager in driving the project by monitoring and tracking planned activities/updates for the project

Project Name: SCB – National Net Settlement Service (NNSS Project) for Cambodia Responsibilities:

- Review VISA card holder global policy for acquiring banks and analyze business cost-saving for SCB
- Lead meetings to assess impacts on implementation scope for SCB and Cambodia branch
- Developed User Requirement Document for SCB and Cambodia branch to sign-off
- Developed business procedures for Cambodia branch to access and settle transactions locally with VISA

Project Name: SCB – S1 Enhancement (Internet Banking) for Cambodia Responsibilities:

- Gather requirement from Product Owner and Business to identify scope of work
- Identify business pain-points and assess impact with vendor
- Developed User Requirement Document for SCB and Cambodia branch to sign-off
- Assisted Project Manager in monitoring vendor planned activities and timeline

Project Name: SCB – Bank of Thailand (BOT) DMS Regulatory Report for bank subsidiaries (Cambodia, Myanmar)

Responsibilities:

- Identified data source for regulatory reports required for BOT submission
- Captured current process for report preparation and manual consolidation work
- Developed User Requirement Document for SCB, Cambodia, and Myanmar branch to sign-off

DECEMBER 2018 - APRIL 2019

IT BUSINESS CONSULTANT / YIP IN TSOI CO., LTD.

Project Name: Government Housing Bank IFRS 9 Project Implementation Responsibilities:

- Review Business Requirement Document (BRD)
- Prepare data mapping documents for ETL developers
- Prepare and walkthrough with clients on upcoming phases of project implementation
- Breakdown high-level requirements for developers
- Discuss and work with technical team in preparation for Functional Requirement Specification (FRS) sign-off
- Draft and submit Functional Requirement Specification (FRS) to bank users for signoff
- Performed Functional Acceptance Test (FAT) to bank users

JULY 2017 - AUGUST 2018

BUSINESS ANALYST / DST WORLDWIDE SERVICES THAILAND LTD.

Project Name: Risk & Compliance Intelligence

Responsibilities:

- Gather requirements through conference call with Product Owner from Vancouver
- Create and translate business requirement into user stories in JIRA
- Perform sprint planning and prioritize user stories in product backlog
- Regular meeting with Product Owner in sharing product roadmap
- Lead meeting with team in clarifying user stories and business requirements
- Assist in assigning and estimate man-hours required for each user story
- Prepare test cases/scenarios for QA testing
- Support QA in developing feature file for automation testing
- Perform sprint review and demo product to Product Owner
- Lead English Learning sessions to team for English proficiency improvement

JULY 2016 – APRIL 2017

BUSINESS ANALYST / ABEAM CONSULTING THAILAND LTD.

Project Name: SAPUP Tipco Project, SAP Implementation Project Responsibilities:

- Gather requirements in sessions with clients
- Work as functional team for Materials Management (SAP Module MM)

- Revise and test add-on programs
- Perform data migration/data conversion from current client system into SAP
- Perform and prepare test scripts for Integration Tests to clients
- Prepare and assist Key User and End Users in User Acceptance Test
- Prepare and revise User Manuals for Key Users and End Users
- Supported users on-site in daily operation for 3 months after new system go-live

EDUCATION

MAY 2016

MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, GLOBAL BUSINESS

COVENTRY UNIVERSITY LONDON CAMPUS

AUGUST 2014

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

MAHIDOL UNIVERSITY INTERNATIONAL COLLEGE

JUNE 2009

HIGHSCHOOL DIPLOMA

RUAMRUDEE INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

CERTIFICATE

JULY 2019

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION: PROFESSIONAL SCRUM MASTER I

SCRUM.ORG

MARCH 2019

INTERNATIONAL FINANCIAL REPORTING STANDARDS (IFRS 9) ON FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS

THE THAI INSTITUTE OF BANKING AND FINANCE ASSOCIATION

SKILLS

- English Fluent
- Project Management
- Vendor Management
- Business Analysis

- JIRA Reporting Tool
- Agile Methodology
- Waterfall Methodology
- Business Process Improvement